[tense music]
All those scrolls you had
Lloyd running around with,
is this what you
were researching?
Not sure I can pull it off.
It's arriving too soon.
Too soon!
What are you saying?
Raccoon? Baboon?
-[crate clatters]
-[Master Wu yelps]
[gasps] Only unity can save us.
Separate, we have no chance.
[thunder crashing]
[knocking]
Ugh, do you know
what time it is?
Trying to get my beauty
sleep here. Boss!
Bunch of jerks that apparently
don't care about my beauty
are here to see you.
-We've come for Jay.
-Whatever you've done to him--
Me? The Merge left
Jay Walker without his memory.
Lost, alone, friendless.
I found him. Helped him
when no one else did.
Where were you?
He's one of us, Ras.
Let him out.
Too late. He's gone.
Jay was here for one
purpose, to win matches.
He failed that purpose,
so I sent him away.
[chain clacking]
If you truly value Jay, leave
the games and go after him.
-Come on, we need to...
-[Riyu rumbles]
What? Maybe we can catch
up to Jay before daylight.
Nya, Ras is playing us.
He sent Jay away because he
wants us to go after him.
Which we will. Right?
Jay needs us.
Not only has he
lost his memories,
he used the Gong of Shattering!
We have to find a way to
heal his inner goodness!
We have to save him!
We do, but this tournament
is a threat to
the Source Dragons,
to the Merged Lands themselves.
If our world is destroyed,
there will be no Jay to save.
Before everything changed,
Master Wu told me,
"Only unity can save us."
Without Jay, we aren't united.
When the games are over,
when the world is saved,
we'll find Jay.
I promise.
-[tender music]
-[footsteps clicking]
-What's wrong?
-During their fight,
Jay told Nya he worked
at the Administration.
Wait, Jay is Agent Walker?
Yeah, the only
person who might know
what happened to my parents.
Great. So when this is all
over, we'll go find him.
Then we can find your parents!
But when will this all be over?
Lloyd promised we'd
find my parents before.
Now he promised
Nya we'd find Jay.
But something always
gets in the way.
♪ Lost in the unknown,
so much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[flame roaring]
-[metal creaking]
-[Nya grunting]
Nya's training technique
appears more
aggressive than usual.
-[Nya yelling and screaming]
-[wood cracking]
You mean angrier?
I can't blame her.
She's working
through some stuff.
She asked to be left alone.
[Zane] But the games
will resume shortly.
She'll be there when we
need her. She always is.
-[Nya yelling]
-[fists thumping]
Poison, Shade, and, what
does this guy have again?
Elemental power of looking mean?
Ugh! This is impossible!
There's too many! [groans]]
Sora, studying your
opponents is good prep,
but you gotta find calm.
Master Wu once said,
"The garden of confidence
grows in the soil of calm,
not the rocks of panic."
My confidence isn't a garden.
It isn't even a shrub.
I'm pretty much
all rocks of panic.
What if I'm up against
Cinder or Nokt?
They can do Shatterspin!
I can't even do Spinjitzu!
These games are often
not about strength,
but about out-maneuvering
your opponent.
Zane's right. And Spinjitzu
is within your reach.
You've got the
fundamentals down.
Look, I know the games
are getting more intense
and it's affecting all of us.
But remember, we're here for
more than just this competition.
The mystery of the
Matriarch's death
is somehow connected
to the games.
And Ras wants to win badly,
so our job is to
make sure he doesn't.
Even if it means winning
ourselves. We can do this.
And he doesn't think
he's a good leader.
[Kai] Riyu? Can you hear me?
[Riyu grumbles]
Riyu, don't give up.
We have to tell you something
before the other
three come back.
[fireworks exploding]
Are you ready?
I think you're. Yeah!
When they talk about the
Tournament of the Sources,
they often say
"Legendary" and "Mythic."
But now they'll also say
"Mega-tight" and "Stang-zoot"
a new word I just made up.
Let the games continue!
Get your umbrella hats on
'cause it's about to
rain elemental powers!
First up today, it's the ninja
with cat ears and no fears.
Sora, Elemental
Master of Technology!
[crowd whooping and cheering]
-All right, Sora.
-You can do this.
Versus the liquid warrior
who will never bore ya'.
From the Azure Reef,
it's Kizzy, Elemental
Master of Balance!
-You can do this.
-You got this, Sora.
[crowd cheering]
Okay, maybe I can do this.
These two masters
will face the high-wire
obstacle extravaganza.
The first to beat their
opponent to the finish line
and kick the kettle drum wins.
Stang-zoot, am I right?
[spirited upbeat music]
-[bell clangs]
-Go, go, go, go!
[Sora yelps]
[tense music]
-[Kizzy whirring]
-[crowd applauds]
[Sora] Whoa.
Sora's competing against the
Elemental Master of Balance
on a tightrope.
How is this even fair?
Have some faith in her.
Let's hope she has
faith in herself.
[metallic clanging]
[Sora] If Kizzy can use her
elemental power, so can I!
[Roby] What's this?
Our Elemental Master of Tech
is turning her
obstacle into a tool!
"Noice!"
[Sora screams, groans]
-[flames hissing]
-[Kizzy whirring]
[Roby] Whoa, Kizzy's showing
the fighting spirit
that makes the
Reefling Water-Tides
the Lords of Coral Corral!
[weapon whirring]
[flames booming]
[Sora groans]
Sorry, can't hang.
Got a drum to kick!
Just like Rontu taught me.
Jump, spin-kick, and through!
-[Sora groans]
-[flames booming]
[jubilant music]
We have a winner.
[crowd cheering]
No hard feelings, Kiz?
Master Kizzy, transfer time.
[powers crackling]
Sora, you are now the
Elemental Master of Technology
and Balance.
Up next, she's smoking hot
and likes to fight a lot.
It's Wyldfyre, Elemental
Master of Heat!
Oh, yeah.
Versus the cloudy man
with the smoky hands!
Cinder, Elemental
Master of, poof, Smoke.
Yes, finally! Payback time!
[Roby] Whoo, a classic.
Capture the flag!
First to get it out
of the circle wins!
Wyldfyre, I know you're itching
to take revenge for Kai,
but we got bigger
things to focus on.
Just go for the flag
and win the game.
Don't worry, coach.
I'll cream him.
[bell clangs]
-[flames hissing]
-[tense music]
Wyldfyre, just grab the flag
before it's too late
-and they use the...
-[gong clangs]
-Oh, no.
-Oh, yeah.
[Cinder booms]
-[Wyldfyre yelps]
-[crowd clapping]
[Wyldfyre groans]
[Cinder whirs and booms]
[tense music continues]
-[crowd gasps]
-C'mon on, Wyldfyre. Get up!
-[Cinder booms]
-[Wyldfyre yelps]
[all gasping]
-[crowd cheering]
-We have a winner. Whoop!
[gasps] What happened?
Are you okay?
I'm totally stang-zoot.
That curtain of fire was
amazing, BT-dub.
Sorry, but I have to
transfer your powers now.
-[Wyldfyre sighs]
-[powers crackling]
[crowd cheering]
-[jubilant music]
[scoffs] They shouldn't
even be allowed
to use the Gong of Shattering.
It's not fair.
I thought the same
thing after Jay used it,
but in combing
through the rules,
I found there is
technically no prohibition
on the use of such items.
Which Ras must have known.
[sniffs] Do you guys smell that?
[sniffs] It's not me, right?
I never know when it's me.
[wind whooshing]
The loser and her loser friends.
What do you want, Cinder?
Hey, if it helps,
you never stood
a chance in there, kid.
Your mentor was Kai.
Get taught by a loser, all you
learn is how is lose, right?
[Wyldfyre yells]
[laughs] You seriously just
tried to blast your power?
You forgot already?
Bet I already know how to use
this power better than you.
[fireball booms]
[security bots chittering]
Dragons don't need
fire to fight. [groans]
[Cinder yelps]
-What the...?
-[Cinder yelping and groaning]
[hover plate whirring]
[groans] Please don't hurt me.
I just wanted to
say congratulations.
Please, please! Mercy!
Such behavior defies logic.
Break up those rabble-rousers.
Ninja, ganging up on the victor
that defeated your teammate.
We haven't seen such
unsportsmanlike behavior
in generations.
No, you've got it all wrong.
[growling]
Lloyd, it's a set up!
Don't foist your
excuses off on us.
We saw the whole
thing on-screen!
Bullying isn't tolerated.
It's disqualification
and immediate exile.
But we didn't, that's not--
Security bots, escort the ninja
beyond the city gates!
[security bots chittering]
Halt! I invoke article 764!
The Cavern Run?
No one's done that in eons.
I totally know the rule book
inside and out
but for those who might not
have devoted
the hours of patient study,
I definitely have,
please fill us in?
It is a trial of worthiness.
Compete in a dangerous,
high-speed vehicle race
through deadly caverns,
beat the clock,
and get immunity from exile.
A desperate race against
the odds? Pure drama!
Stang-zoot, let's do it!
But it's. But, uh...
Come on, Uncle Bleckt,
you love old-school
traditional rules.
This is your jam!
[sighs] I cannot deny the
legitimacy of article 764.
Yes! We race tonight.
I knew my games would
be the sweetest ever.
Sounds like we need a vehicle.
One problem,
we don't have a vehicle.
I'd let you use mine,
but it got trashed
on our way up here.
Bleckt told me they dumped
it in their junkyard.
[laughs] Thanks, Bleckt.
There's a junkyard up here?
That might be
exactly what's needed
for someone with Elemental
Technology powers.
[footsteps slapping]
[Kai] Riyu, we're putting
all our hope in you. Please!
[Riyu whimpers]
-[weapons whooshing]
-[footsteps tapping]
[Riyu whimpers]
[crowd chattering]
Still don't have any wheels?
You gonna beat the
Cavern Run on foot?
[engine revving]
-[engine roaring]
-[tires screeching]
[crowd cheering]
[bold music]
Whoa!
What were you saying, Cinder?
[crowd cheering]
Arin, all eyes will
be on the race,
including theirs.
So it's a good time
for a certain detective
to do some detectiving.
I know that's not a word,
but it sounded right
in the moment.
Detective-away.
Racers, to your vehicle!
[engine revving]
The ninja will be
racing the clock, right?
Well, meet the clock!
The Pace Dragon!
That racing stripe? My addition.
The Pace Dragon
will fly the course
at the exact rate
needed to win the race.
If the ninja beat the
Pace Dragon, victory!
Zero-percent exile!
High stakes, Lloyd.
Win this, the ninja
are still in the games.
Lose, you're out.
Do you have the
leadership skills
to get your team across
the finish line in time?
[Lloyd] Guess we'll find out.
Yes, yes, we will!
Pure drama. Stang-zoot!
[crowd cheering]
Three, two, one. Go, go, go!
-[engine roaring]
-[crowd cheering]
Woo-hoo.
[spirited music]
-[tires squealing]
-[engine roaring]
Bye-bye, buddy.
See you at the finish line.
[tense music]
[rattling]
-Riyu?
-[Riyu grumbles]
I was wondering where you were.
So you're investigating too?
[Riyu chitters]
[footsteps tapping]
[door swishing]
Okay, I'm searching for
anything that connects Ras
to what happened with the
Matriarch or the attacker bots.
-[Kai] Can you hear me?
-[Riyu grumbles]
Well, what is it?
You hear something?
[Kai] It's Riyu.
[Riyu rumbling]
I don't hear anything,
buddy.
[Kai] Are you there, boy?
Um, okay, I guess you're
working on your own lead.
[wooden tapping]
Sora was right.
Frak is working for Ras.
[gasps] Doesn't he know
the guy is pure evil?
Is Frak evil now too?
-[Riyu sniffing]
-[wooden tapping]
[Riyu grumbles]
[Kai] Riyu. I hear you, buddy!
Ah, it's like you're right
next to me all of a sudden
[Riyu whining]
Riyu, what's going on?
Are you talking to a stone?
'Cause, no judgment,
but that's kind of weird.
[Riyu chittering]
[Kai] What? Is someone with you?
I can only hear you.
I don't get it.
It's just a stone.
I've never seen one glow
like that before though.
What's it made of?
[Riyu growling]
[tense music]
[engine roaring]
[Sora] You know,
they had me worried,
but this race is a breeze.
We are so far ahead
of that Pace Dragon.
And according to this, we're
heading into the Green Zone.
Huh, sounds pleasant.
[engine roaring]
-[goo squelching]
-[tires squealing]
Huh? Wait, toxic goo?
Not pleasant. Way not pleasant.
-[engine roaring]
-[dramatic music]
Arin and his pet dragon.
Just like I suspected.
Did your master, Lloyd,
set you up for this?
Sending in one of
the youngest ninja,
and the only one without
an elemental power,
into enemy territory
seems like Lloyd's
brand of leadership.
I didn't need powers
to take you out
at the Ritual of the Blood Moon.
[laughs] She really never
told you. You didn't hit me.
Your little friend
used her tech abilities
to power the object
that struck me.
No, I did it! Sora would've
told me if I didn't.
[Kai] Riyu, what's going on?
Is... Is something happening?
I can't hear you.
Sora is hiding
the truth from you.
Yet another lie from
your so-called teammates.
Covering up for their inability
to train you, perhaps?
I get all the training I need.
Arin, you know that's not true.
The cycle of mastery eludes you.
You obviously have potential.
If Lloyd Garmadon is incapable
of unleashing that potential...
[sighs] ...perhaps you
need another master.
One who sees you more clearly.
Who? You?
I'd never join you.
Your friend Frak
doesn't have an issue
with being on my side.
He must not know
how evil you are!
Is it evil to want
to reverse the Merge?
Wait, you wanna what?
[Riyu grumbles]
-[engine roaring]
-[tires squealing]
[Sora] Hold tight.
[dramatic music]
[goo squelching]
-[engine roaring]
-[tires squealing]
[Lloyd] Sora, up front!
[Sora] Oh, no!
You speak of evil.
The Merge, that was
truly an act of evil.
And since the Merge is what
took your parents away from you,
I'm surprised you'd ever side
with the students of the
very person that caused it.
[Arin] What?
You don't know?
Your ninja's beloved
mentor, Master Wu.
If it wasn't for him,
your parents never
would have been lost.
What are you talking about?
The Merge was
caused by Master Wu.
[dramatic music]
[closing theme music plays]